<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"> <id>/</id><title>alaedine</title><subtitle>My Blog created with jekyll ssgn and chirpy theme</subtitle> <updated>2021-03-09T02:20:11+01:00</updated> <author> <name>alaedine</name> <uri>/</uri> </author><link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="/feed.xml"/><link rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en-US" href="/"/> <generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.0">Jekyll</generator> <rights> © 2021 alaedine </rights> <icon>/assets/img/favicons/favicon.ico</icon> <logo>/assets/img/favicons/favicon-96x96.png</logo> <entry><title>Solve your first Crackme</title><link href="/posts/first-crackme/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Solve your first Crackme" /><published>2021-03-08T00:00:00+01:00</published> <updated>2021-03-09T02:19:35+01:00</updated> <id>/posts/first-crackme/</id> <content src="/posts/first-crackme/" /> <author> <name>alaedine</name> </author> <category term="explained" /> <summary> Hi everyone. In this blog post I will be explaining how to solve a simple beginner crackme. Reverse engineering What we will be doing now is called reverse engineering. As a programmer you develop you program by first making a design of it, you try to understand first how your program will behave in a lot of conditions, then you will implement this design into code with the help of a programm... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>What is /etc/passwd and /etc/shadow files</title><link href="/posts/passwd-shadow/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What is /etc/passwd and /etc/shadow files" /><published>2021-03-07T00:00:00+01:00</published> <updated>2021-03-07T00:00:00+01:00</updated> <id>/posts/passwd-shadow/</id> <content src="/posts/passwd-shadow/" /> <author> <name>alaedine</name> </author> <category term="explained" /> <summary> Hi everyone. In this blog post I will be explaining what is the difference between /etc/passwd and /etc/shadow as it always confuse new comers to linux prerequisite In Linux, a user is identified using a unique identifier called as user id (UID). Each user belongs to at least one group called the user’s primary group. Like user, a group is also identified with the help of a unique identifier ... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>Understanding soft and hard links in linux and how they are used?</title><link href="/posts/understanding-soft-and-hard-links/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Understanding soft and hard links in linux and how they are used?" /><published>2021-03-06T00:00:00+01:00</published> <updated>2021-03-06T00:00:00+01:00</updated> <id>/posts/understanding-soft-and-hard-links/</id> <content src="/posts/understanding-soft-and-hard-links/" /> <author> <name>alaedine</name> </author> <category term="explained" /> <summary> One of the concepts a person will surely encounter on his journey of learning linux is dealing with soft or hard links . It easily confuse people so I hope this Post will make it more clear :) Hard links Let’s say we have a file which is stored in a spot on the hard drive, if you make a hard link of that file you will create another one who point to the same spot as the first file so if your ... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>What happens when you type gcc main.c ?</title><link href="/posts/typing-gcc/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What happens when you type gcc main.c ?" /><published>2021-03-06T00:00:00+01:00</published> <updated>2021-03-06T00:00:00+01:00</updated> <id>/posts/typing-gcc/</id> <content src="/posts/typing-gcc/" /> <author> <name>alaedine</name> </author> <category term="explained" /> <summary> Hi everyone. In this blog post I will be explaining what happens when you compile your C program with gcc . What is Gcc ? First GCC is the GNU COMPILER COLLECTION it’s a set of compilers who can support different programming languages and a lot of architectures . Mainly used in linux system, It was used first to compile C language which was used to write the linux kernel . generating an execu... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>C static libraries . Definition and how to use them</title><link href="/posts/static-libraries/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="C static libraries . Definition and how to use them" /><published>2021-03-06T00:00:00+01:00</published> <updated>2021-03-06T00:00:00+01:00</updated> <id>/posts/static-libraries/</id> <content src="/posts/static-libraries/" /> <author> <name>alaedine</name> </author> <category term="explained" /> <summary> Hello guys, in this Post I will explain what are libraries, why we use them and how to create a custom one. what is a library Libraries consist of a set of related functions to perform a common task. for example, the standard C library, libc.a, is automatically linked into your programs by the “gcc” compiler . Standard system libraries are usually found in /lib and /usr/lib/ directories. Chec... </summary> </entry> </feed>
